Guide to the T.W. Bonner Physics Laboratory records, Rice University UA 442
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
T.W. Bonner Physics Laboratory records, Rice University
1957-1995
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 442
5 Linear Feet 5 boxes
Physics course evaluations, grant funded research applications, experiment notes, related to the T.W. Bonner Lab at Rice University.
Biographical / Historical
Opened in 1953, the Rice Nuclear Laboratory would later become known as the Bonner Laboratory. It was named in dedication to the late Tom W. Bonner who was a renowned nuclear physicist both in the local community and internationally. The lab was designed by Abel Pierce and George F. Pierce Jr. The Bonner Lab was originally home to one particle accelerator, a Mega Electron Volt Van de Graaff machine. A second particle accelerator was acquired in 1961. The Bonner Lab was the United States' first fully equipped nuclear laboratory based out of a university. Major discoveries and accomplishments in the field of nuclear physics were discovered in the Bonner Lab. The two particle accelerators were donated to other laboratories in 1972 and the Bonner Lab was used for music practice and performance as well as computational engineering. In 1994, the Bonner Lab building was demolished. The laboratory was located where Duncan Hall is now.
Content Description
Physics course evaluations, grant funded research applications, experiment notes, related to the T.W. Bonner Lab at Rice University.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center. Please request boxes by contacting woodson@rice.edu or 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred in 2021 by Dr. Paul Padley, Interim Vice President for IT and Chief Information Officer, Professor, Director of the T.W. Bonner Laboratory, via Fondren physics librarian, Debra Kolah.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Physics; Laboratories--Study and teaching; Education
Document Types
syllabi; letters (correspondence); notes
- Series I: Academic Materials: Experiments, Theorems, Research
  - 637 Q 1, 1970-07-1970-11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 637 Q 2, 1970-07-1970-11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Turpin "Paper", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - H.E. pp elastic, 1983-08-18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Pd → Ndπ, 1974-04-04 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hypernuclei (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - (P. Δ++) Reaction, 1983-03-14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - LUG Talk, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cluster Model, 1975-04 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Monopoles, 1982-02-01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charge Symmetry, 1981-07-21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bell's Theorem, 1978-02 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Paris Potential, 1980-09-1984-02 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - P-A Experiments + Theory, 1982-07-1985-06 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Weak Interactions Theory, 1973-07-12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Glueballs, 1983-05-1983-08 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - CP Violation, 1983-08-25 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Deut Loss in Spectrum, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - E 635 Transparencies, 1980-05-1980-11 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 635, 6, 7 Papers, 1982-03 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 64, 65, 66, 125, 129, 1971-04-1978-06 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 635 - pd, 1979-11-1983-04 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 637 XPNCS, 1980-11-19 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 542 Exparencies (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Form Factor (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fermi Gas Model (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Notes (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Notes (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Hyperon Polarization - Theory, 1967-11-1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hyperon Polarization - Review + Summary, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Calculations 817 - Production Xsects (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Quark Spin Dynamics, 1983-07-21-1988-08-01 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Particle Production Charged Hyperon Beam, 1971-07-23-1979 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - πP, γP → Λ PoL, 1977-08-02 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Search for Hyperon Polarization, 1975-09-25-1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - E817: Current Problems, 1985-09-07 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - E817, 1975-05-15-1984-11 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - E817 References, 1978-12-18-1988-07-01 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Precision Tests of CPT and Gravity, 1989-01-19-1990-02-19 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Charged Hyperon Polarization, 1981-03-30-1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - CP + Hyperons, 1985-07-08-1987-08 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - π - P→ Σ° k° (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - PP Talk, 1983-11 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Charmonium Spectroscopy, 1983-1986-11-17 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - High Pₜ Exclusive (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The ξ (2220), 1984-01-18-1984-07-05 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - πP → ζP, 1980-11-01-1984-09-19 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - e⁻ Cooling, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - RICE p Gravity Work, 1985-04-24-1986-04 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - LAS - CEBAF, 1987-09-28-1988-02-25 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - EOTVOS et seq., 1952-03-1986-04-30 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Density Matrix + PoL Parameters, 1961-05-26-1964-11-04 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Errors + Optimization (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Multiple Scattering Correction (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Nucleon-Nucleon Scattering, 1961-08-17-1972-09-18 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - AMPLE Committee Presentation, 1986-05-26-1987-08-11 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - p Beam and cc Spectrum 1, 1981-02-01-1986-11 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - p Beam and cc Spectrum 2, 1980-06-02-1985-01-01 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dodder - TRI, 1981-08-13 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - F.C. Rhanna (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Notes (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 541 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - BNL - Physics Department Talk, 1988-09-21 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Wicks Limit + Optical TH (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Theory + Supermultiplets (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - JARMIE/p Gravity (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Phase Space and "All That Jazz" (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Top Q. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - TAC/SSC Graduate Course on TV (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - p Gravity Talks (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - p Exparencies 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - p Exparencies 2 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - g(p) xpᴺ⁽ᴿ⁾ (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - More p Gravity (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Gravity Expts. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - University of Washington Trap Paper (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Trap - Multiring (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Expts. with Trapped p (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - B. Bonner Talk g(p) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - RFQ Decelerate (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Radiative Association + Ionization (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - e⁻ Affinities and Atom (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Charged Particle in Mag Field (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - H Prodᴺ (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - e⁻ Plasmas (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - e⁺ Beams (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cooling Particles in Trap (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Experiments with Trapped p's (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cylindrical Traps (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mainz Trap Papers (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - TAMU Trap Papers (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - p Trap Notes + Calculations (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - University of Michigan Trap Papers (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Beam Cooling (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - p Trap (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - More Cooling Trap (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Super Magnet (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Polarized Sources (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Phase Shift Analysis (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Gravitational Force of the Autoproton (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Amplitudes (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Spin Transfer Effects (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Deuteron Transfer Polarization (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Vector Polarization (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Feeble Intermediate Range Forces (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Newtonian Gravity Measurement Constraints (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Antiproton RFQ Decelerator (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Reanalysis of Eötvös Experiment (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Gravitational Properties of Antimatter (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Series II: Events: Meetings, Workshops, Committees, Contracts, etc.
  - TSAPS, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - RAND Workshop, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Bonner Talk at APS Meeting, 1976-10 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - BM Cooling Workshop, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - AAPT Conference, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - FNAL P Workshop, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - TM 17 Meetings, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - BNL, 1988-09-21 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - DNP Long Range Plan, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - MEP Review (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Post Workshop FNAL, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Cline Workshop, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Madison P Workshop, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Fermilab P Workshop, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Polarized Proton Beam Meeting, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - BNL P Workshop, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - HEPAP, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - DNP, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Phys/SPAC Merger Committee, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PS 200 Collaboration Meeting, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - TX HEP/URA Meeting, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Corres. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bonner Corres., 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Crocker Corres. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Adjunct Appointments, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Review/Texts (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Memos, Etc. on Relations with SPA (Teaching in Physics), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - P Grav. - DOE Meetings (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 541a, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - APS Summer Internship, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - FNAL Committee for LEP's (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Kinsey's Visiting Committee, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - QM, 1991-11 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - SSC Def. Symposium, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Los Alamos Collab Meeting, 1987-01 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Los Alamos Contract, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Los Alamos Contract, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - BL Fac. Meeting, 1992-04 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Department Meeting, 1992-03 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Grad Committee, 1992-03 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - DNP Meeting Asilomar, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - LUGI, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - UG Education Committee, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Cables (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Visitors → BL, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - BL Computing (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - TSAPS Meeting Austin, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - TSAPS, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - DOE Review, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - DOE Visit, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - TSAPS - University of Houston, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - DOE Request for Info, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - PVAMU, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - APS Meeting, 1994-04 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - DOE Presentation, 1994-03 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - DOE Visit, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - PETₓ/SSC, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - TNRLC, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - RUMPS Meeting, 1991-04 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - APS Scholarship, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Physics/Space Physics Merger Committee, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Vermejo Park Trip, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Series III: Personal Files
  - Letters to Bill Bonner (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - PJR (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Paul Stevenson (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Mike MᶜNaughton (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Ken Ford - AIP (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Hertzog (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - J Roberts (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sun Tsu-Hsun (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Charles Prescott - CV (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Billy Bonner/Washington Trip (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Makdisi (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Susan Bonner-Weir (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - I Stancu (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Goldman, Nieto, & Hughes (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - J Byrne (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Finances: Budgets, Funds, Grants
  - Shell Grant - HoDNE (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Shell Annual Grant (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Texaco Fellowship (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - DOE Budgets Current (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - MEP - DOE Budget (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - HEP Grant Application Budget (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Bonner Lab VAX (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - HEP $ Crisis, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Physics Department Funds (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - AGSE 791 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Los Alamos Budget (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Tax Benefit Selection (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Series V: Class Materials: Proposals, Handouts, Peer Reviews, Schedules, etc.
  - Senior Research Proposals, 1989-09 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 431 Proposals, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - P431 Proposals, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Physics Development Plan (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - B'HAM Proposal (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - g(p) DOE Proposal (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - PSCC Proposal Questions Response (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Physics Department Goals + Proposal (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Original Copy Proposal 817 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 431 Schedule (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - P430 Handouts (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Physics 430 Class Info (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Physics 541a Class Info (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 432 Info + Handouts (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Peer Reviews (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Physics 431 class notes, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 37)